Register of the Russia Missiia (Greece) Records, 1874-1925
Hoover Institution Archives
- RUSSIANS IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES, 1915-1925
  - Refugee organizations
    - Komitet russkoi kolonii v Vengrii (Committee of Russian Colony in Hungary) (Folder 6)
    - Komitet trudovoi pomoshchi russkim (Russian Employment Assistance Committee), Athens. See Komitet pomoshchi russkim
    - Konstantinopol'skii komitet chlenov Zakonodatel'nykh palat Rossii (Constantinople Committee of Members of Russian Legislative Chambers) (Folder 7)
    - Kreditnoe predpriiatie russkikh v Konstantinopole (Russian Credit Enterprise in Constantinople) (Folder 8)
    - Ob"edinenie russkikh emigrantskikh studencheskikh organizatsii (Union of Russian Emigre Student Organizations) (Folder 9)
    - Obshchestvo edineniia russkikh emigrantov v Soluni (Society of Unity of Russian Emigrants in Thessalonike) (Folder 10)
    - Obshchestvo russkikh ofitserov, nakhodiashchikhsia v Afinakh (Society of Russian Army Officers Living in Athens) (Folder 11)
    - Obshchestvo vzaimopomoshchi ofitserov russkoi armii v Gretsii (Russian Army Officers' Mutual Assistance Society in Greece) (Folder 12)
    - Organizatsiia zashchity interesov russkikh emigrantov v Gretsii (Organization for Defense of Russian Emigre interests in Greece)
      - 1922 (Folder 13)
      - 1924 (Folder 14)
      - 1925 (Folder 15)
    - Rossiiskii finansovo-promyshlenno-torgovyi soiuz (Russian Financial Industrial and Commercial Union), Paris (Folder 16)
    - Rossiiskoe obshchestvo Krasnogo kresta (Russian Red Cross Society)
      - General
        - Bulletin (Folder 17)
        - Correspondence
          - Unidentified (Folder 18)
          - Byrdin, B. (Folder 19)
          - Papavasiliu?, D. (Folder 20)
          - Polomin, A. (Folder 21)
        - Death certificates, identifications and other personal documents
          - Agaseev, Dmitrii (Folder 22)
          - Beliavskii, Akim (Folder 23)
          - Buvin, Vladimir (Folder 24)
          - Cherniavskii, Nikolai (Folder 25)
          - Chuev, Nikolai (Folder 26)
          - El'man, David (Folder 27)
          - Gmiro, Vasilii (Folder 28)
          - Gosdava-Kovetskii, Boris. See also Chuev, Nikolai (Folder 29)
          - Kolinenko, Konstantin (Folder 30)
          - Kornilov, German (Folder 31)
          - Krovets, Ivan. See Kornilov, German
          - Kulakov, Evgenii (Folder 32)
          - Kuznetsov, Igor'. See Kolinenko, Konstantin
          - Miasoedov-Ivanov, Vladimir (Folder 33)
          - Mikhailov, Fedor (Folder 34)
          - Podushkin, German. See Buvin, Vladimir
          - Reb, Pavel (Folder 35)
          - Ryzhkov, Aleksandr (Folder 36)
          - Saradzh, Vladimir. See Reb, Pavel
          - Shul'zhenko, Aleksandr. See Kolinenko, Konstantin
          - Slobodiniuk, Mikhail. See El'man, David
          - Solov'ev, Aleksei (Folder 37)
        - Financial records
          - n.d. (Folder 38)
          - 1920-1921 (Folder 39)
          - 1923 (Folder 40-41)
          - 1924
            - March (Folder 42)
            - April (Box 82., Folder 1)
            - June (Folder 2)
            - July (Folder 3)
            - August (Folder 4)
            - September (Folder 5)
            - October (Folder 6)
            - November (Folder 7)
            - November-December (Folder 8)
            - December (Folder 9)
          - 1925
            - January (Folder 10)
            - February (Folder 11)
            - March (Folder 12)
            - April (Folder 13)
            - May (Folder 14)
            - June (Folder 15)
            - July (Folder 16)
            - August (Folder 17)
            - November-December (Folder 18)
        - Identifications. See Death certificates
        - Notes (Folder 19)
      - Athens
        - 1923 (Folder 20)
        - 1924 (Folder 21)
        - 1925 (Folder 22)
      - Donors
        - Greek Government
          - General (Folder 23)
          - Konsul'skaia komissiia dlia nabliudeniia za raskhodovaniem summ, otpuskaemykh grecheskim pravitel'stvom (Consular Control Commission on Greek Government Donations) -- Board sessions. Minutes and report (Folder 24)
        - Societe des Dames Syriennes de Bienfaisance a Bouenos Aires (Folder 25)
      - Moskovskii otriad. See Odesskii otriad
      - Odesskii otriad (Folder 26)
      - Pireus
        - General
          - n.d. (Folder 27)
          - 1920 (Folder 28-29)
          - 1921 (Box 83., Folder 1)
          - 1923 (Folder 2)
        - Hospital
          - 1917-1919
            - French delegation (Folder 3)
            - Greek Red Cross (Folder 4)
          - 1920 (Folder 5)
        - Obshchezhitie rossiiskikh bezhentsev v Piree (Hostel of Russian Refugees in Pireus)
          - 1921 (Folder 6)
          - 1922 (Folder 7)
          - 1923 (Folder 8)
        - Warehouse. See General
      - Thessalonike
        - All-British Appeal -- Donor (Folder 9)
        - Hospital. See also All-British Appeal
          - n.d. (Folder 10)
          - 1918 (Folder 11)
          - 1919 (Folder 12)
          - 1920 (Folder 13)
          - 1921 (Folder 14)
        - Recipients of grants and loans (Folder 15)
    - Russkii natsional'nyi komitet (Russian National Committee)
      - 1922
        - General (Folder 16)
        - Minutes (Folder 17)
      - 1923 (Folder 18)
    - Russkii osvoboditel'nyi komitet (Russian Liberation Committee) (Folder 19)
    - Russkii otvetstvennyi finansovyi komitet (Russian Responsible Financial Committee)
      - General (Folder 20)
      - Bank notes. See Securities
      - Cash accounts (Box 84., Folder 1-2)
      - Lists of recipients (Folder 3-5)
      - Minutes of board sessions (Folder 6)
      - Petitions. See also Lists of recipients (Box 85., Folder 1)
      - Receipts. See also Lists of recipients (Folder 2)
      - Securities
        - Bazarevskii, Aleksandr (Folder 3)
        - Bobrovskii, Petr (Folder 4)
        - Fomin, Iurii (Folder 5)
        - Khomot'iano, Mariia (Folder 6)
        - Kolyshkevich, Tikhon (Folder 7)
        - Lazarev, Aleksandr (Folder 8)
        - Medvedskii, Nikolai (Folder 9)
        - Nikonov, Sergei (Folder 10)
        - Novotortseva, Nina (Folder 11)
        - Petrovskaia, Varvara (Folder 12)
        - Rudnev, Vsevolod (Folder 13)
        - Shishkin, Georgii (Folder 14)
        - Skriagin, Georgii (Folder 15)
        - Steven, Aleks. (Folder 16)
        - Suslova, Elizaveta (Folder 17)
        - Suslova, Tat'iana. See Suslova, Elizaveta
      - Statutes (Folder 18)
    - Russkoe telegrafnoe agenstvo (Russian Telegraph Agency) (Folder 19)
    - Soiuz pomoshchi russkim v Gretsii (Russian Assistance Union in Greece)
      - 1918 (Folder 20)
      - 1920 (Folder 21)
      - 1921
        - General (Folder 22)
        - Golokolosov, Ivan (Folder 23)
      - 1921-1923 (Box 86., Folder 1)
    - Soiuz russkikh uvechnykh voinov v Gretsii (Russian Mutilated Veterans Union in Greece) (Folder 2)
    - Soiuz vozrozhdeniia Rossii v edinenii s soiuznikami (Union for Revival of Russia in Unity with the Allies)
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Organizatsionnoe biuro (Organizational Bureau) (Folder 4)
    - Sovet natsional'nogo i demokraticheskogo bloka russkikh politicheskikh organizatsii zagranitsei (Council of National and Democratic Bloc of Russian Political Organizations Abroad) (Folder 5)
    - Upravlenie Glavnoupolnomochennogo po ustroistvu russkikh bezhentsev v Korolevstve Serbov, Khorvatov i Sloventsev (Administration of Commissioner General for Russian Refugee Assistance in the Kingdom of the Serbs, Croats and Slovenes) (Folder 6)
    - Vserossiiskii zemskii soiuz (All-Russian Zemstvos Union) (Folder 7)
  - Requisitions by the Greek Government
    - Lopatin's trucks (Folder 8)
    - Treaty of 1850, Interpretation of (Folder 9)
  - Russian church. See League of Nations/ 1921-1922
  - Russian schools
    - Egypt (Folder 10)
    - Greece (Folder 11)
  - Russisch-Baltischer Lloyd (Folder 12)
  - Sablin. See League of Nations/ 1921-1922
  - Semenov, Grigorii. See Gil'debrandt
  - Serebriakov, Innokentii (Folder 13)
  - Shamshin, Tikhon (Folder 14)
  - Shebeko (Folder 15)
  - Shmidt, Boris (Folder 16)
  - Shul'gin, Mikhail. See Eksportno-importnyi i promyshlennyi bank
  - Sirotin. See Greek police
  - Stevert, A.A. See Krym, Solomon
  - Sviatoi Nikolai, Passenger ship. See Passports/USSR/ General/ 1919-1920
  - Thessalonike
    - General
      - 1921 (Folder 17)
      - 1921-1923 (Folder 18)
    - Russian cemetery (Folder 19)
    - Russian newspaper (Folder 20)
  - Troianovskaia, Ekaterina (Folder 21)
  - Turkey (Folder 22)
  - Unemployed. See Employment
  - USSR
    - Correspondence from and to
      - Finland, 1920 (Box 87., Folder 1)
      - Greece, 1916 (Folder 2)
    - Counterrevolutionary movements. See RUSSIAN IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES/Bolsheviks and Bolshevik sympathizers/ Volianskii, Andrei; RUSSIANS IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES/ Grants and loans/Veterans returning to Russia; RUSSIANS IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES/Passports/USSR; and RUSSIANS IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES/Veterans
    - Intelligence service. See RUSSIANS IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES/Bolsheviks and Bolshevik sympathizers
  - Veterans
    - General
      - n.d. (Folder 3)
      - 1916 (Folder 4)
      - 1918
        - General (Folder 5-6)
        - Crete (Folder 7)
        - Pireus. See Crete
      - 1919
        - General (Folder 8)
        - Athens
          - General (Folder 9)
          - Appeal to the Greek Government (Folder 10)
      - 1920 (Folder 11)
      - 1920-1921 (Folder 12)
      - 1921 (Folder 13)
      - 1922 (Folder 14)
    - Cossacks
      - General (Folder 15)
      - Krasnov's appeal (Folder 16)
      - Students (Folder 17)
    - Sanitary detachment (Folder 18)
  - Volos (Folder 19)
  - Volos and Larisa (Folder 20)
  - Zakhar'in, David (Folder 21)
  - Zarnekau, Nikolai, Count (Folder 22)
  - Za rubezhom (Folder 23)
- AGENT MINISTERSTVA TORGOVLI I PROMYSHLENNOSTI (AGENT 0F TRADE AND INDUSTRY MINISTRY) OFFICE FILE, 1919-1922
  - General
    - Account book (Box 88., Folder 1)
    - Chronological file
      - n.d. (Folder 2)
      - 1919
        - June-September (Folder 3)
        - October (Folder 4)
        - November (Folder 5)
        - December (Folder 6)
      - 1920
        - January-June (Folder 7)
        - July-December (Folder 8)
      - 1921
        - January-May (Folder 9)
        - June-December (Folder 10)
      - 1922 (Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Registers of (Folder 12)
    - Day file
      - Bound (Box 89., Folder 1)
      - Unbound
        - 1919 (Folder 2)
        - 1920
          - January-June (Folder 3)
          - July-December (Folder 4)
    - Lists of commercial products (Folder 5)
  - Animal guts (Folder 6)
  - Aperghi Freres, Jean Constantinides et Co. (Folder 7)
  - Aslanov, Mikhail (Folder 8)
  - Binders (Folder 9)
  - Cacao (Folder 10)
  - Cement
    - 1919 (Folder 11)
    - 1919-1920 (Folder 12)
  - Chaidopoulos, Jean. See Aslanov, Mikhail
  - Corks and cork producing equipment (Folder 13)
  - Cotton (Box 90., Folder 1)
  - Edward Mauer Co., New York (Folder 2)
  - Flour (Folder 3)
  - Glycerine (Folder 4)
  - Golitsyn, Vasilii. See Ing. A. Pira Degiarde & Co.
  - Greco-Russian Cnamber of Commerce (Folder 5)
  - Industrias Megano Agricolas (Folder 6)
  - Ing. A. Pira Degiarde & Co. (Folder 7)
  - Irving National Bank (Folder 8)
  - Kossagovskii, Dmitrii (Folder 9)
  - Laksman, Dmitrii (Folder 10)
  - Lumber. See Kossagovskii, Dmitrii
  - Mantafola Mariono Co. (Folder 11)
  - Munoz y Compania, Murcia, Spain (Folder 12)
  - Paper (Folder 13)
  - Paprika (Folder 14)
  - Russkii torgovyi komitet (Russian Commerce Committee) (Folder 15)
  - Russko-slavianskii bank (Russo-Slavic Bank) of Commerce (Folder 16)
  - Russo-French Chamber of Commerce. See Greco-Russian Chamber
  - Russo-Greek Chamber of Commerce. See Greco-Russian Chamber of Commerce
  - Senokosnikov, T.S. & Co., London (Folder 17)
  - Tabacco
    - Brodskii (Folder 18)
    - Clara, Jules (Folder 19)
    - Norwetor Norsk Aktieselskap (Folder 20)
    - Vvedenskii (Folder 21)
  - Vrangel', Konstantin. See Ing. A. Pira Degiarde & Co.
- OVERSIZE FILE.
  - Account book, 1921-1923 (Box 91.)
- MEMORABILIA.
  - Seals (Box 92.)
- AUDIO-VISUAL.
  - See Photograph Card Catalog (Folder 10.A-V)
Russian Diplomats And Officials Affiliated With The Russian Mission In Greece, 1906-1924
Argiropulo -- --
Official of the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del; Senator
Arsen'ev --
Charge d'Affaires, Romania
Artamonov --
Envoy, Serbia
Artsimovich --
Deputy Minister of Foreign Affairs
Avksent'ev, Nikolai --
President of the Natsional'nyi kongress, Ufa
Bakh --
Charge d'Affaires, Netherlands
Bakh, Genrikh --
Employee of the Russian Embassy, United States
Bakheracht --
Envoy, Switzerland
Bakhmet'ev, Boris --
Ambassador, United States
Bakhmet'ev, George --
Ambassador, United States
Bazili, Nicolas de --
Charge d'Affaires, France
Belanovich --
Employee of the Russian Vice-Consulate, Dedeagach
Beliaev, M. --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Iran
Benkendorf --
Ambassador, Great Britain
Bentkovskii, T.S. --
Official of the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
Chaikovskii, N.V. --
President of the Severnoe pravitel'stvo
Charykov --
Employee of the Russian Embassy, Turkey
Chekmarev, Mikhail --
Official of the Ministertvo inostrannykh del
Chemerzin --
Representative, Ethiopia
Chukhnin --
Admiral
Dolivo-Dobrvol'skii --
Vice-Director of the Pravovoi departament Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Dubiagskii --
Charge d'Affaires, Serbia
Fanderflit --
Director of the Pervyi departament Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Ferkhmin --
Vice-consul, Uskunder
Gadzhemukov --
Vice-consul, Dedeagach
Garshin, Mikhail --
Secretary to Ol'ga Konstantinovna, Queen of Greece
Gartvig --
Envoy, Serbia
Girs, Aleksandr --
Envoy, Montenegro
Girs, Mikhail --
Ambassador, Italy
Golovachev --
Official of the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del, Omsk
Grammatopulo --
Employee of the Russian Embassy, Turkey; Employee of the Russian Mission, Greece
Gudim-Levkovich, Pavel --
MIlitary Agent, Greece
Gul'kevich --
Official of the Vtoroi politicheskii otdel Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Gul'tiaev, Makar --
Servant of the Russian Military Agent, Greece
IAkushev, Boris --
Charge d'Affaires, Greece
Ikskul'-Gil'debrand --
Charge d'Affaires, Greece
Islavin, Lev --
Envoy, Montenegro
Izvol'skii, Aleksandr --
Ambassador, France
Kal', Viktor --
Consul General, Thessalonike
Kalmykov --
Consul, Rhodes
Kapnist --
Deputy Chief of the Morskoi general'nyi shtab
Khadzhi-Lazzaro, Ivan --
Consul, Ioannina
Khomenko --
Admiral
Klimenko --
Employee of the Russian Consulate General, Thessalonike
Kliuchnikov, M. --
Secretary to the President of the Sibirskoe vremennoe pravitel'stvo, Ufa
Kolemin, Georgii --
Chief of the Tsifirnyi otdel of Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
Kotsebu, Count --
Charge d'Affaires, Norway
Krupenskii, Pavel --
Official of the Pervyi politicheskii otdel Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Kudashev --
Ambassador, Spain
Kudashev --
Envoy, China
Kudashev --
Officer of the Stavka
Lamzdorf --
Minister of Foreign Affairs
Lebedev --
Officer at the Commander-in-Chief Headquarters
Leont'ev --
Military Agent, Greece
Lerkhe --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Greece
Lobachev --
Employee of the Russian Consulate General, Thessalonike
Lopukhin --
Director of the Pervyi departament Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Lutskii, M. --
Chief of the Pravovoi otdel Narodnogo komissariata inostrannykh del
Lysakovskii --
Envoy, Vatican
Makalinskii, A. --
Naval Agent, Greece
Maklakov, Vasilii --
Ambassador, France
Marianov, Aleksandr --
Agent of the Ministerstvo torgovli i promyshlennosti, Greece
Mavromati --
Vice-Consul, Mersin
Meiendorf, Mikhail --
Charge d'Affaires, Denmark
Miliukov, Pavel --
Minister of Foreign Affairs
Mukhanov --
Military Agent, Greece
Nabokov, Konstantin --
Charge d'Affaires, Great Britain
Nekliudov --
Official of the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
Neratov, Anatolii --
Deputy Minister of Foreign Affairs; Russian Dipomatic Representative, Turkey
Nevadovskii --
Military Agent, Greece
Nikolaev --
Official of the Vtoroi politicheskii otdel Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Nol'de --
Deputy Minister of Foreign Affairs
Nordman --
Director of the Ekonomicheskii otdel Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Obnorskii --
Charge d'Affaires, Albania
Omel'chenko --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Greece
Papavasiliu --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Greece
Pelekhin --
Charge d'Affaires, Serbia
Persiani --
Charge d'Affaires, Italy
Persiani --
Official of the Tretii politicheskii otdel Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Petriaev --
Official of the Vtoroi politicheskii otdel Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Petrov, N.A. --
Consul, Alexandria
Poggenpol', Nikolai --
Employee of the Russian Embassy, Italy
Poklevskii Kozell, Stanislav --
Envoy, Romania
Pokrovskii, N.N. --
Minister of Foreign Affairs
Poliakov --
Military Agent, Greece
Polovtsov --
Deputy Minister of Foreign Affairs
Priklonskii --
Consul General, Budapest
Pustoshkin, Pavel --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Netherlands
Sabler (Desiatovskii), IUrii --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Bulgaria
Sablin, Evgenii --
Charge d'Affaires, Great Britain
Savinskii, A.P. --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Bulgaria
Sazonov, Sergei --
Minister of Foreign Affairs
Serafimov, Boris --
Russian Representative to the Italian Military Commissioner, Constantinople
Sevastoulo, Matvei --
Charge d'Affaires, France
Shcherbachev, T.S. --
Envoy?, Greece
Shcherbina --
Employee of the Russian Consulate General, Thessalonike
Shebeko --
Envoy, Romania
Shebunin --
Consul, Chania
Shilling --
Official of the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
Shpadierg, Marko --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Greece
Shtiurmer, B.V. --
Minister of Foreign Affairs
Shtrandtman, M. --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Greece
Shtrandtman, V. --
Envoy, Serbia
Shumskoi --
Official of the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
Smirnov --
Envoy, Egypt
Solov'ev --
Charge d'Affaires, Spain
Sukin --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Greece
Svechin --
Envoy, Netherlands
Sverbeev --
Employee of the Russian Embassy, Germany
Tarnovskii --
Military Agent, Serbia
Tatarinov --
Military Agent, China
Tatishchev --
Envoy, Greece
Tatishchev --
Official of the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
Taube, Konstantin --
Official of the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
Tereshchenko --
Minister of Foreign Affairs
Trubetskoi --
Ambassador, Italy
Tukholka --
Employee of the Russian Consulate, Chania
Urusov, S.L. --
Employee of the Russian Mission, Greece
Van der Giukht, Nikolai --
Employee of the Russian Consulate, Ioannina; Employee of the Russian Consulate, Pireus
Vil'chkovkii --
Assistant to the Russian Military Agent, Greece
Vinaver --
Minister of Foreign Affairs
Volanis, Nikifor --
Chorister, Russian Church, Athens
Vologodskii, Petr --
Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Vremennoe sibirskoe pravitel'stvo
Zhukovskii --
Official of the Ministerstva inostrannykh del
Zinov'ev --
Ambassador, Turke
Zubruzhitskii, Vladimir --
Assistant to the Naval Agent, Greece; Vice-Consul, Dedeagach
Zuev --
Employee of the Russian Consulate, Chania